Lester Gaynor Class of 1949 Memorabilia Collection MS217
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Lester Gaynor Class of 1949 Memorabilia Collection
1947 -- 1949
1947 -- 1986
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Gaynor, Lester
MS217
0.65 Linear Feet
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into two series: Memorabilia and correspondence and Unprocessed accessions.
Custodial History
Collection donated to Digital Collections and Archives by Laurie Gaynor, daughter of Lester Gaynor, in February 2014. In April 2015 Ms. Gaynor donated additional materials, which were added to the collection.
Scope and Contents
This collection documents Lester Gaynor's life as an Engineering student and active alum. It contains correspondence, news clippings, event brochures and invitations, class pins and buttons, and professional organization membership cards. The collection also contains a Distinguished Service Award that was granted by the Tufts University Alumni Association to Lester's wife, Mildred Gaynor, in 1968 for her work with the Neponset Valley Tufts Club.
Biographical / Historical
Lester Gaynor graduated with an undergraduate Engineering degree from Tufts College in 1949. While at Tufts, he was a member of the student chapter of the American Society of Civil Engineers and the Tau Beta Pi fraternity.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Alumni collections; University history; Tufts University -- History; Gaynor, Lester
- Memorabilia and correspondence, 1947 -- 1986; 1947 -- 1949; MS217.001; 0.2 Linear Feet
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains correspondence, news clippings, event brochures and invitations, class pins and buttons, and professional organization membership cards. The collection also contains a Distinguished Service Award that was granted by the Tufts University Alumni Association to Lester's wife, Mildred Gaynor, in 1968 for her work with the Neponset Valley Tufts Club.
  Arrangement
  This series is not arranged.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  - Membership Cards, 1947 -- 1949; MS217.001.001.00001 (Box 1)
  - Tau Beta Pi Brochures, 1947 -- 1949; MS217.001.001.00002 (Box 1)
  - Event Invitations, 1949; MS217.001.001.00003 (Box 1)
  - Tufts Napkins, 1969; MS217.001.001.00004 (Box 1)
  - Senior Class Promenade, 1949; MS217.001.001.00005 (Box 1)
  - Junior Prom, 1948; MS217.001.001.00006 (Box 1)
  - Mid-Winter Informal, 1949; MS217.001.001.00007 (Box 1)
  - Tufts College Commencement Exercises, 1949; MS217.001.001.00008 (Box 1)
  - Class of 1949 Fifth Reunion, 1954; MS217.001.001.00009 (Box 1)
  - Class of 1949 20th Reunion Pin, 1969; MS217.001.001.00010 (Box 1)
  - Class of 1949 35th Reunion Pin, 1984; MS217.001.001.00011 (Box 1)
  - Tufts Engineering Council Pin, 1949; MS217.001.001.00012 (Box 1)
  - Tau Beta Pi Fraternity Pin, 1949; MS217.001.001.00013 (Box 1)
  - New England Highway Exposition Pin, 1949 -- 1969; MS217.001.001.00014 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, News Clippings, and Programs, 1949 -- 1986; MS217.001.001.00015 (Box 1)
- Additional accessions, 1949 -- 1983; MS217.002; 1 Volumes
  This series includes Gaynor's Class of 1949 memorabilia, School of Engineering diploma, reunion memorabilia, correspondence (as an alum) with the School of Engineering, and alumni award plaque.
  - Memorabilia, alumni award, correspondence with School of Engineering, 1949 -- 1983; MS217-001 (Box 1)
  - School of Engineering diploma, 1949-06-18; MS217-002 (Box Large Map Case 3 Drawer 10)